荣誉出品
最专业冰火字幕
专注GOT剧集
翻译   千耳
翻译   Rubilacxe
翻译   imzxz1051
君临 King's Landing
翻译   陌客之子
红堡
Red Keep
校对   小恶魔透明子
校对   盗墓奸尸
卡林湾
Moat Cailin
临冬城
Winterfell
时间轴   poplar
后期    弃疗的林家闻
监制    临冬城的狮子
监制     北落师门
绝境长城 the Wall
最专业的华语冰火资料站：                         中文维基
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/
百度冰与火之歌贴吧  &  百度权力的游戏贴吧    联合出品
史诗图书  正统奇幻的圣殿
布拉佛斯
Braavos
策划    baozhenyuawabi
特别顾问   屈畅(ccxx)@史诗图书
弥林
Meereen
根据长篇小说
《冰与火之歌》 改编
原著  乔治·R·R·马丁
衣柜字幕组
更多冰火资讯
请扫码关注“黑城堡”微信平台
微信号：HEICHENGBAO
第八集   The Mountain and the Viper
比武决斗
我们到了
Here we are
准备好了？
Ready?
“卡斯特梅的雨季”
"The Rains of Castamere."
你他妈的是聋子？
You fucking deaf?
这个调子你每次都他妈的猜错
Same wrong guess every fucking time.
听着 你这个傻逼
Listen, you cunt.
噢！
Oh!
是“狗熊与美少女”
"The Bear and the Maiden Fair."
总算有个带耳朵的
There's a man with an ear.
可惜你的鸡巴只有指甲刺儿那么大
Too bad you got a hangnail for a cock.
第一次看到你脱裤子的时候
First time I saw you with your breeches down,
我以为你是个太监
I thought you were a eunuch.
你们都见过的 姑娘们
You've seen it, girls.
就像刚从壳里钻出来的小蜗牛
Like a baby snail peeking out of his shell.
你的孩子早上一直在哭
Your baby was crying this morning.
吉莉
卡斯特的女儿和妻子
把我吵醒了
Woke me up.
听见我说的吗？
You hear me?
嗯
Yes.
那好 有什么想说的？
Well, got anything to say?
我很抱歉 他把你吵醒了
I'm sorry he woke you up.
老娘不稀罕你的抱歉
I don't care if you're sorry.
你不让他安静点
Keep that baby quiet
我可动手了
or I will.
你不许碰他
Don't you ever touch him.
野人的小婊子
Little wildling bitch.
你应该和你的同类待在一起
You should have stayed with your own kind.
你在听我说话吗？
You listening to me?
— 闭嘴  — 你说什么？
- Shut your mouth. - What?
就是一只猫头鹰 你这个白痴婊子
It's just an owl, you dumb bitch.
不 不是的
No, it's not.
托蒙德
“巨人克星” 野人
耶哥蕊特
“火吻而生” 野人
斯迪
瑟恩的马格拿 野人
—— 嘘
-- Shh.
山姆威尔·塔利
“杀手” 守夜人事务官
我真不该把她留在那儿
I should never have left her there.
— 你不可能提前知道  — 我当然能知道
- You couldn't have known. - Of course I could've known.
他们一直在洗劫附近的村子
They've been raiding the villages close by.
他们在屠杀我们的兄弟 我们却龟缩在这里
And we just cower in here while they slaughter our brothers.
葛兰
“笨牛” 守夜人游骑兵
我们的兄弟应该按命令待在黑城堡
Our brothers had orders to stay at Castle Black.
所以就心安理得了？黑杰克和木桶还有
So it's all right, then? Black Jack and Kegs
穆利活该被砍成碎片 因为他们没遵守命令？
and Mully chopped to pieces 'cause they broke the rules?
我不是这个意思
I didn't say it was all right.
艾迪森·托勒特
“忧郁的艾迪” 守夜人事务官
我是说他们不该在那儿
I'm saying they shouldn't have been there.
我们曾发誓要保卫百姓们的领土
We're pledged to guard the realms of men.
因为我 她死了
She's dead because of me.
我们居然连鼹鼠村都保卫不了
We can't even guard Mole's Town.
琼恩·雪诺
守夜人事务官
我们不能去追击他们 你明白的
We can't go after them. You know that.
他们正希望如此
It's what they want.
还有小山姆
And little Sam.
就好像是我亲手割断了他们的脖子
As if I cut their throat myself.
也许她藏起来了
Maybe she managed to hide herself.
之前我也以为你们都死了
I thought all of you was dead.
你们和莫尔蒙一起去了北方 一个都没回来
You went north with Mormont and no one came back.
派普尔
“派普” 守夜人
很久都没回来
Not for ages.
但是最后你们还是回来了
But then you did.
她在卡斯特手上活了下来
She survived Craster
他是我见过的最恶心的狗屎
and he was the worst shit I've ever met.
她在去长城的长途跋涉中活了下来
She survived the long march to the Wall.
她还竟然他妈的从异鬼手上活了下来
She survived a white walker, for fuck's sake.
她可能已经出村了
She might have got out.
有可能
She might have.
如果他们袭击了鼹鼠村
If they hit Mole's Town,
下一个就轮到我们这儿了
then we're next.
曼斯和他的军队肯定就在附近
Mance and his army must be close.
他们有十万人
100,000 of them.
我们还剩多少 一百零五个？
And there's what, 105 of us left?
你算上黑杰克 木桶和穆利了吧？
You counting Black Jack, Kegs, and Mully?
一百零二
102.
一百零二个人要怎么阻挡十万大军？
How do 102 men stop 100,000?
活到最后的那个 行行好
Whoever dies last, be a good lad
把我们都烧了吧
and burn the rest of us.
要是我和这个世界说拜拜了
Once I'm done with this world,
我可不想再回来
I don't want to come back.
灰虫子
无垢者指挥官
弥桑黛
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安的侍女
你觉得他在监视你？
You think he was spying on you?
不 不是监视
No, not spying.
多斯拉克人觉得外族人很可笑
The Dothraki think outsiders are ridiculous
居然会对赤身裸体感到羞耻
taking shame in the naked body.
他们在星空下做爱 让整个卡拉萨都能看见
They make love under the stars for the whole khalasar to see.
丹妮莉丝·坦格利安
“风暴降生” 龙之母
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
不过你不是多斯拉克人
But you are not Dothraki.
不是
No.
好了 我不明白这事有什么问题
Well, I don't see why it matters.
灰虫子不会有兴趣的
Grey Worm isn't interested.
无垢者不在乎我们衣服下面是什么
None of the Unsullied care what's under our clothes.
他有兴趣
He was interested.
什么？
What?
我相信他有兴趣
I believe he was interested.
奴隶主阉割男孩的时候
When the slavers castrate the boys,
是不是都弄走了？
do they take all of it?
什么都弄走了？
All of it?
唔——
The--
柱子和石头
the pillar and the stones.
我不知道 陛下
I don't know, Your Grace.
你从来不好奇么？
Haven't you ever wondered?
是的 陛下
Yes, Your Grace.
弥桑黛
Missandei.
我是来道歉的
不需要道歉
我希望没有吓着你
没有
你给窝上的通用语课
The lessons you give I in common tongue...
对窝来说很宝贵
these are precious to I.
— 对我来说  — 对我来说
- To me. - To me.
我不记得教过你“宝贵”这个词
I don't remember teaching you the word precious.
那个安达尔人乔拉 他教了窝——
Jorah the Andal, he teaches I--
他教了我这个词
he teaches me this word.
你还记得自己出生时的名字么？
Do you remember the name you were given at birth?
我什么都不记得
I remember nothing.
只记得自己是个无垢者
Only Unsullied.
他们什么时候阉你的
When they cut you,
你还记得么？
do you remember that?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
他们对你做了那种事 我感到抱歉
I'm sorry they did that to you.
为什么？为什么道歉？
Why? Why sorry?
对男孩做这种事太残忍了
It's a terrible thing to do to a boy.
如果奴隶主们没阉了我
If the masters never cut me,
我就当不成无垢者
I never am Unsullied.
“风暴降生”丹妮莉丝下令杀奴隶主们的时候
I never stand in the Plaza of Pride
我就不会站在骄傲广场
when Daenerys Stormborn orders us to kill the masters.
我就不会被选为无垢者的首领
I never am chosen to lead the Unsullied.
我就不会遇到来自纳斯岛的
I never meet Missandei
弥桑黛
from the island of Naath.
对不起 我——
I am sorry I--
为今天的事
for today.
对不起
I am sorry.
灰虫子
你那样看着我让我很高兴
我也是
海怪 嗯
Kraken. Mmm.
只要呆在海里它们就很强
Strong as long as they're in the sea.
拉姆斯·雪诺
卢斯·波顿的私生子
一旦从水里出来
When you take them out of the water,
因为没有骨头
no bones.
它们引以为傲的重量会把它们压垮
They collapse under their proud weight
“臭佬”
席恩·葛雷乔伊
塌成一堆废物
and slump into a heap of nothing.
你以为它们明白这点
You'd think they know that.
但很不幸 它们没那么聪明
Unfortunately, they're not very bright.
你打算对他们说什么？
What do you tell them?
我是席恩·葛雷乔伊
I'm Theon Greyjoy,
巴隆之子 铁群岛的继承人
son of Balon, heir to the Iron Islands.
— 那你到底是个什么东西？ — 我是臭佬
- And what are you really? - I'm Reek.
你确定？
Are you sure?
你看起来很像个领主
You do look very much like a lord.
又威严又骄傲
Formidable, proud.
我是臭佬
I'm Reek.
直到何时？
Until when?
一直
Always.
— 永远  — 那就对了
- Forever. - That's right.
直到你烂在地里
Until you're rotting in the ground.
记住你是谁 你不是谁
Remember what you are and what you're not.
把卡林湾献给我
Bring me Moat Cailin.
不许靠近
No closer.
你是谁？
Who are you?
我是肯宁
I'm Kenning,
这个要塞的指挥官
commander of this garrison.
你说你是席恩·葛雷乔伊？
And you say you're Theon Greyjoy?
是的
Yes.
我为什么要信你？
And why should I believe that?
我生在派克岛上 是巴隆·葛雷乔伊的儿子
I was born on Pyke to Balon Greyjoy.
他的三子 也是唯一还活着的儿子
His third and last living son.
我是你们的王子
I am your prince.
我向淹神发誓
I swear it by the Drowned God.
逝者不死
What is dead may never die.
既然你是我的王子
And if you were my prince,
为什么你和波顿的军队在一起？
why are you marching with a Bolton army?
临冬城一役后 波顿大人俘虏了我
Lord Bolton took me captive after Winterfell.
他派我来和你们诚心诚意的谈判
He sent me to treat with you in good faith
和你们这些铁民
as your fellow ironborn.
波顿大人想要干嘛？
And what does Lord Bolton want?
你们在疾病中渐渐消亡
You are fading from sickness,
你们严重短兵缺将
you are badly outnumbered,
而且你们离海太远
and you're hundreds of miles from the sea.
波顿大人请求你们保护好自己的人
Lord Bolton implores you to protect your men
放弃这座守不住的堡垒
and abandon this fortress you can no longer hold.
只要你们答应 他就会公平公正地对待你们
Do this, and he will be just and fair with you
就像对我那样
as he has been with me.
波顿军会确保一条通往磐石海岸的安全通道
The Boltons will give you safe passage to the Stony Shore.
他希望我们投降？
He wants us to surrender?
我的亲生父亲 你们的国王
My own father, your king,
很多年前曾向劳勃·拜拉席恩投降
surrendered years ago to Robert Baratheon.
我看着他屈膝下跪
I watched him bend the knee.
没有丝毫耻辱
There was no shame there.
他战斗得光荣 和你们一样
He fought with honor, as did you.
“没有耻辱” “战斗得光荣”
"No shame." "Fought with honor."
抱歉 我没听清
I'm sorry, I didn't hear.
“没有耻辱” “战斗地光荣”
"No shame." "Fought with honor."
只有夹着尾巴的狗才会这么说
Only a whipped dog would speak this way.
或是女人
Or a woman.
你是女人么 小鬼？
Are you a woman, boy?
你不知道——
You don't know--
铁种绝不投降
The ironborn will not surrender.
臭佬 我叫臭佬……
Reek. My name is Reek...
你去告诉你的主人
You go tell your master that,
席恩·葛雷乔伊
Theon Greyjoy,
或者无论他妈的什么人
or whoever the fuck you are.
我叫臭佬
My name is Reek.
你他妈的到底在嘀咕些什么？
What in the hell are you muttering?
我是臭佬
I'm Reek.
臭佬
Reek.
如果我们投降 就能活命？
If we yield, we live?
这张纸上是这么说的么？
Is that what it says on this paper here?
是的 让你的人挂上白旗打开大门
Yes. Have your men raise the white flag and open the gates.
你们就能回家
You're going home.
你不会真以为我会放他们回去吧？
You didn't really think I'd let them go, did you?
剥皮已经不再流行了
It's fallen out of fashion, flaying.
让人难过 但现状如此
Sad, but true.
传统非常重要
Traditions are important.
没有历史我们算什么？
Where are we without our history?
- 嗯？ - 是的 大人
- Eh? - Yes, my lord.
我们现在可以回家么？
Will we go home now?
当然可以
I believe we will.
回我们的新家
To our new home.
你有外族人的血统 是么 贝里席？
You have foreign blood, don't you, Baelish?
是的 我的曾祖父来自布拉佛斯
A great-grandfather from Braavos, yes.
培提尔·贝里席
“小指头” 赫伦堡公爵
峡谷守护者
我想我们的祖先
I suppose all of our ancestors
原本都来自其他一些地方
came from somewhere else originally.
我们的祖先早在数千年前
Our forebearers settled the Vale
就在谷地定居
thousands of years ago.
之后我们击退了无数的入侵者
We've fought off invaders ever since.
谷地的美丽
The beauty of the Vale is matched only
只有这里伟大的贵族家族能与之相配
by the nobility of its great families.
艾林夫人常常对我提起
Lady Arryn often told me
你就是她的坚石 罗伊斯大人
that you were her rock, Lord Royce.
她从未跟我提起过你 贝里席
She told me nothing about you, Baelish.
但也用不着她跟我说
But I didn't need to hear from her.
放债人 皮条客
Moneylender. Whoremonger.
You've been licking Tywin Lannister's boots so long,
你给泰温·兰尼斯特舔鞋子舔了这么久
- 舌头还没舔黑可真是个奇迹 - 大人——
- it's a wonder your tongue's not black. - My lord--
当琼恩·艾林任命你做财政大臣时 没人在乎
And when Jon Arryn named you Master of Coin, no one cared.
反正是一份肮脏的工作
Always been a grubby job.
约恩·罗伊斯
“青铜约恩” 谷地领主
为何不让一个肮脏的人做呢？
Why not let a grubby man do it?
但当我听说你躲在这里
But when I heard you were lurking here,
巴结讨好艾林女士——
fawning over the Lady Arryn--
艾林女士邀请我来这里
Lady Arryn invited me.
我们从小就非常亲密
She and I have been close since childhood.
安雅·韦伍德
谷地领主
是啊 我们都知道你们有多亲密
Yes, we all know how close you were.
艾林女士的偏好是她自己的事
Lady Arryn's predilections were her own affair.
可我们不能坐视她的死亡
Her death is our affair.
凡斯·科布瑞
谷地领主
当然 她的自杀让我们都非常震惊
Of course. Her suicide shattered us all.
她确实有点古怪
She was an odd fish.
每个人都知道 但自杀？
Everyone knew that. But suicide?
她深深爱着她的孩子
She adored that boy of hers.
我不认为她会抛弃他 不会是自愿的
I don't see her abandoning him. Not by choice.
奇怪的是你刚到这里没几天
Strange that within days of your arrival,
艾林女士就和你成婚 然后就掉下了月门
you've married Lady Arryn and she's fallen through the Moon Door.
她总是容易陷入忧郁
She was always prone to melancholy.
艾林女士并不像我们一样适应这个残酷的世界
My lady wasn't meant for a world as brutal as ours.
我们听说当时还有人在场 一个女孩
We were told there was a witness. A girl.
我想是你的一个侄女
A niece of yours, I believe.
一个啥都不懂的蠢姑娘
A girl with no learning and scattered wits.
我向你们保证 她帮不上什么忙
I assure you, she would be of no help.
我们想跟她谈谈
We'd like to speak with her.
- 我去带她过来 - 不用了
- Let me fetch her. -  No need.
我们想听听她没受人影响的证词
We prefer to hear her testimony unadulterated.
珊莎·史塔克
小恶魔的妻子
靠近点 孩子
Come closer, child.
你无须害怕我们 也不用怕他
You have nothing to fear from us or him.
这位贝里席大人是你的叔叔？
Lord Baelish here is your uncle?
你的名字是阿莲？
Your name is Alayne?
也许让贝里席大人离开 你会更自在一些
Perhaps you would feel more comfortable if Lord Baelish left the room.
- 女士—— - 我没在问你
- My lady-- - I wasn't asking you.
- 他可以留下 -大声点 女孩 你可不是一只该死的小老鼠
- He can stay. - Speak up, girl, you're not a damn kitchen mouse.
告诉我们你看到了什么
Tell us what you saw.
对不起 贝里席大人
I'm sorry, Lord Baelish.
我必须说出事实
I have to tell the truth.
我会把一切都告诉你们
I'll tell you everything.
请说吧 阿莲 什么也不要隐瞒
Please, Alayne, leave nothing out.
我的名字并不是阿莲
My name is not Alayne.
而是珊莎·史塔克
It's Sansa Stark,
艾德·史塔克公爵的长女
eldest daughter of Lord Eddard Stark.
罗伊斯大人 您拜访临冬城时我们曾见过面
Lord Royce, we met when you came to Winterfell.
您当时正送您的儿子威玛爵士前往长城
You were escorting your son Ser Waymar to the Wall.
珊莎·史塔克？
Sansa Stark?
你竟然当着我面撒谎 你这卑鄙小人？
You tell lies right to my face, you little worm?
贝里席大人说过很多谎话
Lord Baelish has told many lies.
但都是为了保护我
All to protect me.
自从我的父亲被处决后
Since my father was executed,
我就成了君临城里的人质
I have been a hostage in King's Landing.
一个让乔佛里蹂躏
A plaything for Joffrey to torture
让瑟曦太后折磨的玩物
or Queen Cersei to torment.
他们打我 羞辱我
They beat me, they humiliated me,
他们把我嫁给小恶魔
they married me to the Imp.
在君临城我没有朋友……
I had no friends in King's Landing...
除了他
except one.
他救了我
He saved me.
寻找时机把我偷偷带了出来
Smuggled me away when he had the chance.
他知道我在鹰巢城
He knew I'd be safe here in the Eyrie
和我的血亲莱莎姨妈在一起会很安全
with my own blood, my Aunt Lysa.
但兰尼斯特在哪里都有朋友
The Lannisters have friends everywhere.
甚至是谷地
Even the Vale.
他让我发誓不跟任何人说我的真实身份
He made me swear not to tell anyone my true name.
你的秘密在这里很安全 小姐
Your secret is safe with us, my lady.
你的父亲就在这些厅堂里长大
Your father grew up right here in these halls.
我们经常一起打猎
We hunted together many times.
他是个好人
He was a fine man.
告诉我们你的姨妈发生了什么事 珊莎
Tell us what happened to your aunt, Sansa.
你们很了解她 大人 夫人
You knew her well, my lords, my lady.
你们知道她有些问题
You knew she was a troubled woman.
她一直爱着贝里席大人
She always loved Lord Baelish.
她亲口对我说的
She told me herself.
从他到奔流城的那一刻起
From the moment he arrived at the gates of Riverrun,
一个八岁的男孩 一个小麻袋装着他所有的财物
a boy of eight carrying everything he owned in a little sack.
她向我坦诚自己从未爱过艾林大人
She confessed to me she never loved Lord Arryn.
她只不过是听从父亲的命令 就像我们许多人一样
She did as her father commanded, as so many of us have.
现在诸神终于让她和贝里席大人结合
When the gods finally allowed her to be with Lord Baelish,
她非常高兴
she was so happy.
但却没持续多久
For a time.
我的姨妈是个善妒的女人
My aunt was a jealous lady.
她担心贝里席大人
She was terrified that Lord Baelish
会不再爱她
didn't love her anymore.
会为了别的年轻女人抛弃她
That he would abandon her for a younger woman.
后来……
And then...
有一天她看到他亲了我
one day she saw him kiss me.
珊莎小姐
Lady Sansa.
只是脸颊上的轻轻一吻 罗伊斯大人 仅此而已
It was a peck on the cheek, Lord Royce, nothing more.
通过联姻 现在我真的成了贝里席大人的侄女
Lord Baelish is my uncle now, in truth, by marriage.
他一直都对我很好
He's always been so kind to me.
我很高兴能呆在这里 能重获自由
I was so happy to be here, to be free.
而这些都是因为他
All because of him.
可姨妈却把矛头指向我
But my aunt turned on me.
她诅咒我 管我叫荡妇
She cursed me. Called me a whore.
还发誓要把我丢下月门
Promised to throw me through the Moon Door.
而当贝里席大人试着让她冷静下来时
When Lord Baelish tried to calm her,
她打了他
she struck him.
她说她再也不想活了
She said she didn't want to live anymore.
她就站在月门边上
She stood on the edge of that Moon Door.
他想方设法去说服她
He tried to reason with her.
向她保证她是自己唯一爱过的人
Promised her she was the only one he had ever loved,
但她还是踏了出去 她——
but she stepped through those doors and she was--
嘘
Shh.
嘘 这不是你的错 乖女孩
Shh, it's not your fault, sweet girl.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
从她养育那男孩的方式就能看出来
You could see it in the way she raised that boy.
都十岁了还要亲自用奶子为他哺乳
Feeding him from her own teats when he was 10 years old.
罗伊斯大人！ 现在不是说这个的时候
Lord Royce! This is hardly the time.
我向您道歉 女士
Apologies, my lady.
还有你 贝里席
And to you as well, Baelish.
我们对你有些苛刻
We treated you a bit harshly.
这没什么好抱怨的
You want justice, Lord Royce.
你寻求正义 罗伊斯大人
I can hardly complain about that.
我也一样
I want the same.
自杀这种事可没什么正义可伸张 不是么？
Not much justice to be meted out in suicide, is there?
对莱莎而言 没有 但对她的儿子呢？
For Lysa, no. But for her son?
仅仅二十年前 谷地的骑士
Only 20 years ago, the knights of the Vale
跟随着琼恩·艾林 奈德·史塔克和劳勃·拜拉席恩
rode behind Jon Arryn, Ned Stark, Robert Baratheon.
并肩战斗 击败了疯王
They fought together to overcome the Mad King.
而在那之后 艾林和罗伊斯
And since then, Arryn and Royce,
科布瑞 韦伍德
Corbray, Waynwood,
所有这些谷地的大家族都作壁上观
all the great houses of the Vale watched from the corner.
就像胆小男孩一样看着这场混乱争斗
A timid boy at a tavern brawl.
你在质疑我们的勇气么？
Are you questioning our courage?
我想知道你们站在哪一边
I want to know which side you're on.
难道你们支持兰尼斯特？
Do you support the Lannisters,
这个家族可是处决了你们的好友奈德·史塔克啊
the house that executed your friend Ned Stark?
我们当然不会支持该死的兰尼斯特
Of course we don't support the damn Lannisters.
不会么？凯特琳·史塔克向她的妹妹乞求支援 却被莱莎拒绝了
No? Catelyn Stark begged her sister for support and Lysa refused.
通过置身于这场争斗之外 你们让泰温·兰尼斯特
By staying out of the fray, you've allowed Tywin Lannister
彻底的消灭了他的每一个对手
to destroy his rivals on every compass point.
现在还有谁反抗他？
Who stands against him now?
你想我们支持谁 贝里席大人？
Who would you have us back, Lord Baelish?
罗柏·史塔克已经死了
Robb Stark is dead.
我想你们支持罗宾·艾林
I'd have you back Robin Arryn,
谷地公爵
Lord of the Vale.
罗宾·艾林是个病弱的小男孩
Robin Arryn is a sickly little boy.
而病弱的小男孩也可以成长为强大的男人
And sickly little boys sometimes become powerful men.
更常见的是夭折早逝
More often they die young.
我全身心的爱慕着莱莎
I adored Lysa with all my heart.
但她太爱她的儿子了 简直就是溺爱
But she loved her son so much, she became overprotective.
他得学习如何使剑
He needs to learn how to swing a sword.
如何骑马
How to ride a horse.
是啊 该学了  - 的确如此
- Aye, it's time. - Yes, it's time.
是时候安排他巡游谷地
Time for him to tour the Vale,
拜访他治下的所有城堡了
to visit all the castles in his domain.
是时候让小鸟儿罗宾离巢喽
Time for Robin to leave the nest.
巴利斯坦爵士
Ser Barristan.
什么事？
Yes?
谁派你来的？
Who sent you?
巴利斯坦·赛尔弥
“无畏的” 女王铁卫
弥林
渊凯
雅洛斯岛
狭海
君临
- 巴利斯坦爵士 - 乔拉爵士
- Ser Barristan. - Ser Jorah.
乔拉·莫尔蒙
“大熊”
我错过御前会议了？
Have I forgotten a council meeting?
没有
No.
这是什么？
What's this?
皇家赦免令
A royal pardon
由劳勃·拜拉席恩签署
signed by Robert Baratheon.
你监视过她
You spied on her.
谁给你的？
Who gave you this?
这重要吗？
Does it matter?
你告诉她了？
Have you told her?
我想先光明正大地告知你
I wanted to tell you first, man-to-man
而非暗中告密
rather than go behind your back.
让我单独跟她解释吧
Let me speak with her in private.
从今往后你不得再与她独处
You'll never be alone with her again.
篡夺者为何赦免你？
Why did the usurper pardon you?
可容我私下解释
If we could speak alone.
不行 有话就在这讲
No, speak to me here.
解释给我听
Explain it to me.
您认为是谁送此物到弥林的？
Who do you think sent this to Meereen?
谁能从中获益？
Who profits?
这是泰温·兰尼斯特的伎俩啊
This is the work of Tywin Lannister.
他想离间我们
He wants to divide us.
一旦窝里斗起来 我们就无暇对抗他了
If we're fighting each other, we're not fighting him.
赦免令是在你我相遇那年签署的
The pardon was signed the year we met.
你到底因何被赦免？
Why were you pardoned?
难不成你想说文件是伪造的
Unless you're saying this document was forged.
并非伪造
It is not forged.
那究竟为何？
Why, then?
我曾为瓦里斯通风报信
I sent letters to Varys,
他是君临的情报总管
the spymaster of King's Landing.
你都对他通报了些什么？
What was the content of these letters?
一些消息 - 什么消息？
- Information. - What information?
您和韦赛里斯抵达潘托斯之事
When you and Viserys arrived in Pentos.
他计划将您下嫁给卓戈卡奥
His plan to marry you to Khal Drogo.
您的大婚之日
When you were married.
还有您哥哥的死讯
When your brother died.
是你告诉他我怀上了卓戈卡奥的孩子？
You told him I was carrying Drogo's child?
我-- -到底是或不是？
- I-- - Yes or no?
-卡丽熙 - 不准这么叫我
- Khaleesi. - Don't call me that.
你是否告诉他我怀上了卓戈卡奥的孩子？
Did you tell him I was carrying Drogo's child?
是
Yes.
那个酒商想要毒杀我
That wine merchant tried to poison me
就因为你的消息
because of your information.
我阻止了您饮下毒酒
I stopped you from drinking his wine.
那是因为你知道酒里有毒
Because you knew it was poisoned.
我只是怀疑而已
I suspected.
你从一开始
You betrayed me
就背叛了我
from the first.
求求您宽恕我
Forgive me.
我从未想过
I never meant--
求求您 卡丽熙 宽恕我
please, Khaleesi, forgive me.
你将我的秘密卖给了杀害我父亲
You sold my secrets to the man who killed my father
并篡夺我哥哥王位的家伙  - 我也曾救过您
- and stole my brother's throne... - I have protected you.
我也曾为您战斗搏杀
Fought for you. Killed for you.
...而你现在倒想要我的宽恕？
...and you want me to forgive you?
我爱上了您
I have loved you.
爱？
Love?
爱？你竟敢提这个字？
Love? How can you say that to me?
换成其他人 我早将他处决了
Any other man, and I would have you executed.
而你 不管是活人还是尸体 我都不愿让你驻留在我的城市
But you, I do not want you in my city dead or alive.
回你在君临的主子身边去
Go back to your masters in King's Landing.
有种去要你的赦免啊
Collect your pardon if you can.
求求你 丹妮莉丝
Daenerys, please.
休想再碰我一下
Don't ever presume to touch me again
休想再直呼我名
or speak my name.
限你今日黄昏前打点好行李
You have until dusk to collect your things
时间一到就给我出城
and leave this city.
次日若你还在弥林逗留
If you're found in Meereen past break of day,
我将命人把你的头颅丢进奴隶湾
I'll have your head thrown into Slaver's Bay.
走吧
Go.
马上
Now.
卡林湾是您的了 父亲
Moat Cailin is yours, Father.
卢斯·波顿
恐怖堡公爵
跟我走走
Walk with me.
洛克那有什么消息没？
Has there been any word from Locke?
没有
No.
倒也无妨
Unimportant.
一个是残废 一个是小屁孩
A cripple, a young boy.
近来也没有哪个北境诸侯见过他俩
None of the northern lords have seen them.
多半已经死了
Dead most likely.
大部分铁民已经逃窜出北境
Most of the ironborn have fled the North.
而且还会越来越多，这都是你的功劳
Now more will follow, thanks to you.
说说你看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
沼泽 平原 丘陵
Moors, fields, hills.
说说你到底看到了什么
Tell me what you see.
什么都没看到
Nothing.
并非如此
Not nothing.
你眼前正是北境
The North.
朝那个方向骑行700里 仍身处北境
Ride 700 miles that way, you're still in the North.
那边得400里
400 miles that way.
而那头得300里
300 miles that way.
北境的面积比其他六大王国加一起还要大
The North is larger than the other six kingdoms combined.
而我身为北境守护
And I am the Warden of the North.
北境已入我囊中
The North is mine.
告诉我 你叫什么名字？
Now tell me, what is your name?
拉姆斯·雪诺
Ramsay Snow.
不对 不是拉姆斯·雪诺了
No, not Ramsay Snow.
拆开读读
Open it.
从今天起直至你逝世之日
From this day until your last day,
你的姓名都是拉姆斯·波顿
you are Ramsay Bolton,
北境守护卢斯·波顿的嫡子
son of Roose Bolton, Warden of the North.
荣幸之至
You honor me.
我发誓将继承发扬您的家族姓氏
I swear I will uphold your name
和传统
and your tradition.
我不会辜负您的厚望 父亲
I will be worthy of you, Father,
我保证
I promise.
快点 臭佬 我得洗个澡喽
Come, Reek, I'll be needing a bath.
请进
Yes?
我初见你时 你还是个孩子
First time I saw you, you were just a child.
一个初到君临的北境少女
A girl from the North come to the capital for the first time.
如今稚气已荡然无存
Not a child any longer.
你为何帮我？
Why did you help me?
要是被他们判为有罪的话
They would have thrown you through the Moon Door
您就会被扔出月门
if they found you guilty.
这不是我要的答案
That's not an answer.
要是您被处决了
If they'd have executed you,
我的下场又会如何呢？
what would they have done with me?
这我不得而知
I don't know.
我也是
Neither do I.
与其把赌注下在陌生人身上
Better to gamble on the man you know
还不如下在熟人身上更可靠对吧？
than the strangers you don't?
而你觉得自己跟我很熟了？
And you think you know me?
我知道您想要什么
I know what you want.
是吗？
Do you?
我还以为自己会很开心呢
I thought it'd make me happy,
但并没有 没那个心情
but it doesn't. Not really.
这世上没什么可开心的
Nothing makes you happy.
我感觉挺多的  - 比如？
- Lots of things make me happy. - Like what?
杀掉波利佛 杀掉罗尔杰什么的
Killing Polliver, killing Rorge.
所以说没法亲手杀掉乔佛里你就不开心了
So you're sad because you didn't get to kill Joffrey yourself.
是不是？
Is that it?
哪怕能让我亲眼看看也好啊
At least I could have been there to watch.
真想看看他意识到自己死到临头时的眼神
I wanted to see the look in his eyes when he knew it was over.
桑铎·克里冈
“猎狗”
艾莉亚·史塔克
没错 那眼神肯定是世上最棒的
Aye, nothing in the world beats that look.
你大半辈子都在护卫他
You protected him for most of his life.
你觉得自己能救下他吗？
You think you could have saved him?
我他妈又不是试毒的
I wasn't the damn wine taster.
小杂种确实该死 但是用毒的话——
Little shit deserved to die, but poison--
下毒是娘儿们的招数
poison's a woman's weapon.
爷儿们用刀剑
Men kill with steel.
你们这么说不过是死要面子罢了
That's your stupid pride talking.
所以你才成不了一个优秀杀手
It's why you'll never be a great killer.
要是没别的武器 我拿鸡骨头也能干掉乔佛里
I'd have killed Joffrey with a chicken bone if I had to.
要真能看到这一幕我愿意花大钱
I'd pay good money to see that.
你真该让我帮你把伤口烙一下
You should have let me burn it.
这种跳蚤咬的伤
It's a fleabite.
这跳蚤可让你的脚力大大下降了
That fleabite's got you walking a lot slower than you used to.
反正也不用走多远了
Well, we won't have to walk too much further.
你真以为我姨妈会花钱赎我？
You really think my aunt will pay for me?
没错 她肯定会给钱
Aye, she'll pay.
我连她面都没见过
I've never even met her.
无所谓 你是她亲戚
Doesn't matter. You're her blood.
她的族语不是家族 荣誉之类的玩意儿吗
Family, honor, all that horseshit.
你们这些贵族老爷淑女整天挂嘴边
It's all you lords and ladies ever talk about.
我又不是淑女
I'm not a lady.
欲过血门者何人？
Who would pass the Bloody Gate?
老子是猎狗 桑铎·克里岗
The bloody Hound, Sandor Clegane.
这位是...
And his...
随行者乃是艾莉亚·史塔克
traveling companion Arya Stark,
你们莱莎·艾林夫人的侄女
niece of your lady Lysa Arryn.
唐纳尔·韦伍德
血门骑士
请您节哀顺变
Then I offer my condolences.
莱莎夫人去世了
Lady Arryn died.
就在三天前
Three days ago.
我从没离开过家呀 培提尔叔叔
I've never left home before, Uncle Petyr.
- 我好害怕  - 您不必害怕
- I'm afraid to leave. - You shouldn't be.
母亲说过身为谷地公爵就该乖乖地待在鹰巢城里
The Lord of the Vale belongs in the Eyrie, Mother said.
外头不安全
She said it's not safe outside.
她待在这儿也不见得安全
It wasn't safe for her inside.
罗宾·艾林
鹰巢城公爵
睡个觉也能死
They die in their beds.
哪怕蹲个夜壶也能蹲死咯
They die squatting over their chamber pots.
早晚都有一死
Everybody dies sooner or later.
别操心自个儿的死法啦
Don't worry about your death.
操心该怎么活吧
Worry about your life.
只要活上一天
Take charge of your life
就要自己做主
for as long as it lasts.
这才是身为谷地公爵该操心的
That is what it means to be Lord of the Vale.
该出发吗？
Shall we go?
酒总是好的
Wine always helps.
多谢了
I thank you for it.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
“小恶魔”
詹姆·兰尼斯特
“弑君者”  御林铁卫队长
比武审判
Trial by combat.
要诸神慧眼识真
Deciding a man's guilt or innocence
裁决一个人是有罪或无辜
in the eyes of the gods
却得搭上两个人往死里对砍
by having two other men hack each other to pieces.
诸神就这德行
Tells you something about the gods.
还有多久？
How much longer?
快了
Soon.
你觉得奥柏伦能赢？
Do you think Oberyn has a chance?
多恩的红毒蛇
The Red Viper of Dorne.
你要不致命上哪弄这么个头衔去 是吧？
You don't get a name like that unless you're deadly, right?
我从没看他打过
I've never seen him fight.
噢  他要死了 我也得玩完
Oh, he's going to die. I'm going to die.
奥柏伦很有自信
Oberyn believes in himself.
说“玩完”都算委婉了
That's putting it mildly.
弑君之罪该怎么判来着？
What's the punishment for regicide?
五马分尸？绞死？
Drawing and quartering? Hanging?
- 车轮刑？- 砍头
- Breaking at the wheel? - Beheading.
会不会太普通了点
Seems rather ordinary.
他还是我亲外甥 这又该怎么算？
And he was my nephew as well, so what is that?
兄弟相残叫“弑兄”
Fratricide is brothers.
杀害儿女叫“弑子”
Filicide is sons.
“弑甥” 这词儿不错
Nepoticide. That's the one.
还有弑母 弑父
Matricide, patricide,
杀婴 自杀
infanticide, suicide.
每种杀人行为都有专门的名词来概括啊
There's no kind of killing that doesn't have its own word.
表亲相杀没有
Cousins.
表亲相杀 没错
Cousins, you're right.
没有专门形容表亲相杀的词儿
There is no word for cousin killing.
真厉害
Well done.
你还记得咱堂兄奥森吗？奥森·兰尼斯特？
Do you remember cousin Orson? Orson Lannister?
当然了 奶妈把他掉地上摔坏了头
Of course. Wet-nurse dropped him on his head.
- 让他变呆了 - 呆？
- Left him simple. - Simple?
他从前在花园里一坐就是一天
Used to sit all day in the garden.
拿个石头砸甲虫
Crushing beetles with a rock.
完全不知道什么快乐
Nothing made him happier.
你也不知道什么是快乐
Nothing made you happier.
因为天生的缺陷
You'd think being tormented from birth
让你觉得自己跟那些可怜人更亲近些
would have given you some affinity for the afflicted.
正相反 只有在嘲笑那些可怜人的时候
On the contrary. Laughing at another person's misery
我才觉得自己跟其他人是平等的
was the only thing that made me feel like everyone else.
傻子看久了就不觉得好笑了
The joke wore thin, though.
那是你 你不看就不看呗
For you. You drifted away.
我有别的爱好
I had other interests.
是啊 别的爱好
Yes, other interests.
我倒是一直陪着奥森
But I stayed with Orson.
为什么？
Why?
我很好奇
I was curious.
他为什么要砸那些甲虫？
Why was he smashing all those beetles?
他从中得到了什么？
What did he get out of it?
一开始我跑去问他
First thing I did was ask him.
“奥森 你砸那么多甲壳虫干嘛？”
"Orson, why are you smashing all those beetles?"
他回答道 “砸甲壳虫”
He gave me an answer. "Smash the beetles.
“砸它们”
Smash 'em."
我没有气馁
I wasn't deterred.
在我认识的所有人中 我就是最聪明的那个
I was the smartest person I knew.
我完全有那个能力去揭开一个
Certainly I had the wherewithal to unravel the mysteries
藏于弱智心中的秘密
that lay at the heart of a moron.
于是我去了瓦拉瑞克学士的书房
So I went to Maester Volarik's library.
那个瓦拉瑞克 他有次想对我动手动脚
Volarik. Tried to touch me once.
结果我发现 有关大人物的著作实在太多
Turns out, far too much has been written about great men
而有关弱智的书却少之又少
and not nearly enough about morons.
真不应该
Doesn't seem right.
总之 我一无所获
In any case, I found nothing
找不到只言片语来解释奥森的鬼德行
that illuminated the nature of Orson's affliction
也搞不清他为什么会坚持不懈地残害那些甲虫
or the reason behind his relentless beetle slaughter.
所以我又回到原点
So I went back to the source.
也许我无法与奥森交谈
I may not have been able to speak with Orson,
但我可以看着他 观察他
but I could observe him, watch him
就像人们通过观察动物
the way men watch animals
从而进一步理解它们的行为那样
to come to a deeper understanding of their behavior.
而我越是观察
And as I watched,
就越确定一点
I became more and more sure of it.
这其中必有奥秘
There was something happening there.
他的脸就像书页一样
His face was like the page of a book
写满了我不懂的语言
written in a language I didn't understand.
但他并不是无意识的 他有自己的动机
But he wasn't mindless. He had his reasons.
我着了魔一样想搞清他的动机
And I became possessed with knowing what they were.
我开始花大把大把的时间来观察他
I began to spend inordinate amounts of time watching him.
我把午饭都端在花园里吃
I would eat my lunch in the garden,
一边咀嚼羊肉一边听着...
chewing my mutton to the music of...
不观察他的时候 我就琢磨他
And when I wasn't watching him, I was thinking about him.
父亲沉迷于家业
Father droned on about the family legacy
而我满脑子都是奥森的甲虫
and I thought about Orson's beetles.
在我读坦格利安征服史的时候
I read the histories of Targaryen conquests.
我听到龙翼的拍打了吗？没有
Did I hear dragon wings? No.
我听到的是……
I heard...
可我还是搞不明白他为什么要那么做
And I still couldn't figure out why he was doing it.
我必须要弄明白 因为这太可怕了
And I had to know, because it was horrible
那些甲虫就那么莫名其妙地被弄死了
that all these beetles should be dying for no reason.
这世上 每一天
Every day around the world,
都有成百上千的男人 女人和孩子被杀害
men, women, and children are murdered by the score.
谁他妈会在乎几只脏兮兮的甲虫啊？
Who gives a dusty fuck about a bunch of beetles?
道理我不是不明白 但我就是害怕得很
I know, I know. But still, it filled me with dread.
一堆又一堆 一年又一年
Piles and piles of them, years and years of them.
究竟有多少活生生的 到处乱爬的小东西
How many countless living crawling things
被活活砸死 血肉干枯 化为尘土？
smashed and dried out and returned to the dirt?
我曾经梦见自己
In my dreams I found myself
站在一堆虫甲上
standing on a beach made of beetle husks
虫甲绵延开去 一望无际
stretching as far as the eye could see.
我大哭着醒来
I woke up crying,
为它们那支离破碎的小小尸体流泪
weeping for their shattered little bodies.
我曾试图阻止奥森
I tried to stop Orson once.
他有你两个那么大
He was twice your size.
他“吭”一声就把我推到一边去
He just pushed me aside with a "kuuh"
然后接着砸
and kept on smashing.
他砸了一天又一天
Every day until that mule
直到那头骡子一蹄正中心口 将他踢死为止
kicked him in the chest and killed him.
那么 你怎么想？
So what do you think?
他为什么这么做？
Why did he do it?
这一切有什么意义？
What was it all about?
我不知道
I don't know.
祝你今天好运
Good luck today.
梅斯·提利尔
高庭公爵 玛格丽·提利尔之父
泰温·兰尼斯特
凯岩城公爵 国王之手
瑟曦·兰尼斯特
太后
瓦里斯
“八爪蜘蛛” 情报总管
这护甲看起来好单薄
Looks like very light armor.
我喜欢灵活移动
I like to move around.
至少也该戴上顶头盔吧
You could at least wear a helmet.
战斗之前你不该喝酒的
You shouldn't drink before a fight.
奥柏伦·马泰尔
“红毒蛇” 多恩亲王
艾拉莉亚·沙德
奥柏伦的情妇
这是你玩竞技场的那几年学来的吗？
You learn this during your years in the fighting pits?
开打前我从来都要喝点
I always drink before a fight.
那会让你送命的 也会让我送命
It could get you killed. It could get me killed.
今天不是我的死期
Today is not the day I die.
你要跟那东西打？
You're going to fight that?
我要宰了那东西
I'm going to kill that.
格雷果·克里冈
“魔山”
他是我见过个头最大的家伙
He is the biggest man I've ever seen.
被放倒以后 个头就不重要了
Size does not matter when you are flat on your back.
诸神保佑
Thank the gods.
在诸神和世人的注视下
In the sight of gods and men,
派席尔
大学士
我们聚首于此
we gather to ascertain
以甄别这位提利昂·兰尼斯特
the guilt or innocence of this...
究竟有罪抑或无辜
man Tyrion Lannister.
愿圣母赐予他们慈悲
May the Mother grant them mercy.
愿天父赐予他们应得的判决
May the Father give them such justice as they deserve.
愿战士指引...
And may the Warrior guide the hand...
...勇士的双手——
...of our champion--
别留我在世上孤身一人
Don't leave me alone in this world.
我绝不
Never.
他们告诉你我是谁了吗？
Have they told you who I am?
某个死人
Some dead man.
我是伊莉亚·马泰尔的弟弟
I am the brother of Elia Martell.
知道我为什么千里迢迢赶来这座
Do you know why I have come all the way to this stinking
屎堆一样臭的城市吗？
shit-pile of a city?
因为你
For you.
我要在你死前听你认罪
I'm going to hear you confess before you die.
你强奸了我姐姐
You raped my sister.
你杀了她
You murdered her.
你害了她孩子
You killed her children.
说出来 我让你死个痛快
Say it now and we can make this quick.
说出来 你奸了她
Say it. You raped her.
你杀了她
You murdered her.
你害了她孩子
You killed her children.
你奸了她！
You raped her!
你杀了她！
You murdered her!
你害了她孩子！
You killed her children!
你奸了她！
You raped her!
你杀了她！
You murdered her!
你害了她孩子！
You killed her children!
等等 你要死了吗？
Wait. Are you dying?
别 别 别
No, no, no.
你不能死 你还没认罪呢
You can't die yet. You haven't confessed.
说出来
Say it.
说出她的名字 伊莉亚·马泰尔
Say her name. Elia Martell.
你奸了她 你害了她孩子
You raped her. You killed her children.
伊莉亚·马泰尔
Elia Martell.
谁给你下的命令？
Who gave you the order?
谁给你下的命令？！
Who gave you the order?!
说出她的名字！
Say her name!
你奸了她！你杀了她！
You raped her! You murdered her!
你害了她孩子！
You killed her children.
说出来 说出她的名字
Say it. Say her name.
说出来！
Say it!
伊莉亚·马泰尔
Elia Martell.
我杀了她的孩子
I killed her children.
我奸了她
Then I raped her.
然后我像这样捣碎了她的脑袋！
Then I smashed her head in like this!
诸神已宣告其意愿
The gods have made their will known.
提利昂·兰尼斯特
Tyrion Lannister,
以拜拉席恩家族的国王
in the name of King Tommen of the House Baratheon,
托曼一世之名
First of His Name,
我在此判处你死刑
you are hereby sentenced to death.
衣柜字幕组出品
维基关键字：奥柏伦·马泰尔    伊莉亚·马泰尔    格雷果·克里冈
席恩·葛雷乔伊   拉姆斯·波顿
剧情没看懂？ 典故不清楚？欢迎登陆 冰火中文维基 查询
http://zh.asoiaf.wikia.com/